oh my
gosh people are doing shanky stuff yeah
I know I know I love it are you
kidding what
[Music]
yo yo yo sup critical thinkers we have a
little bit of a different type of
episode for you guys today okay um and
it all starts with a story I was in Los
Vegas and Mr fron Rosen himself comes up
to me and says Justin I wish I could do
a Swedish accent right now I can't do a
Swedish accent but he says Justin I've
got some amazing research that I want to
share with you and I want you to put out
on the Pod um and when fron says that
you say absolutely let's go record an
episode right now and uh and so we did
and it was awesome and it totally blew
my mind I think you're really going to
enjoy it but it is a presentation um and
it's typically typically on this pod we
try to keep things audio medium friendly
but this one might be the exception you
might want to head over to YouTube for
this one so that you can see what's
going on not to say that you won't be
able to get the general concept from
audio and I think the general concept is
also very valuable um but if you're
looking to see a little bit more the
details of the explation that he had um
then you might see that better on
YouTube so um you can go to the YouTube
channel at ctbb doow it'll redirect you
to the YouTube channel um and then you
should be able to see all of that there
really great research um definitely
recommend it's those uh it's about those
request IDs like X request ID headers um
or X correlation ID headers that you see
in the HTTP requests um pretty much with
every HTTP request to any major
um and how those can allow you to inject
way deep into all the pipelines uh of an
application because that request ID is
used everywhere to correlate requests
and actions that are be T being taken um
so very interesting research kind of
like a like a duh moment like why didn't
I test for this um so definitely
definitely some great content there um
trying to think if there's any other
announcements for today oh um we did
launch the swag store this past week all
right so if you're if you're watching
this which you should be cuz I already
told you to be watching this then you
can see my ctbb t-shirt um got some ctbb
stuff on the back too um there's a bunch
of different designs on there so if you
want to get your hands on some of that
head over to ctbb do ctbb doow ctbb doow
swag that's a little hard to say ctbb
doow swag there we go and uh you can
check out that swag store that we got
set up for you guys um all right I think
that's it enjoy the episode with frons
uh and yeah it's crazy research so get
ready for your mind to be blown all
right
peace cool we're here in Vegas uh fron
fron told me yesterday that there's
going to be some research that was going
to blow my mind so we're going to cover
that and I also want to cover a little
bit of this uh crazy bug bash event that
we are uh that we've witnessed awesome
this past Vegas so all right hit me so
this cimer this might not blow your mind
but rather like oh oh [__] why did I not
think of that that's so it's not like I
I think when I present the title so I
did a I did a talk back in June on
midnight sun which is like a CTF in
Stockholm and when I presented there I
mean it wasn't that many people it was
mostly the CTF people that was just busy
but so I presented this H I hadn't
presented it anywhere else and I haven't
released the slides so I wanted to do it
with you and see see your reaction just
because I think I enjoy it so much and
the impact is is quite nice as well all
right let's see it so so the title will
give it away are you ready I'm ready boo
boom
boooom ex correlation
in okay do you what the heck is this
dude do do you know what that is I
don't okay this is fun this is fun so so
the talk is called EXC correlation
injections okay and the whole idea is to
how to break service ey context um and
what does that mean
probably some form of inje injection
okay so we the discussion here is going
to be struggles of course request
correlation now maybe
is and then service side Json injections
and autoband the RC and blindes okay you
ready oh my gosh dude first impression
what you the mind is spinning okay no no
hit with it hit okay okay this sounds
super easy it's going to sound super
easy it's going to sounds super obvious
and this is I'm going to talk about the
happy path like we struggled with this
for for a long time and but but this is
like straight on to the to the actual
you know
vulnerabilities um and yeah hunting cide
bugs how to reach them deep okay very
like how do I you know look at the front
end as a a as a border or like the API
that you're hitting how can I reach
deeper into your into your
infrastructure uh and one of those are
exporation okay dude I've seen these so
many freaking times dude okay I it's a
you know X request ID X correlation ID
they're everywhere they're customized
some of them are you know named by the
company that has them Etc the whole idea
with them is to correlate every single
action happening down to sometimes
queries to the database uh and the the
idea is to follow one thing so you can
get like TR M you can get everything to
to say that okay this request failed in
our micros service world what type of
things happen going down so this is a so
how I understood this was originally a
essentially a introspection tool for the
blue teams right where it's like okay uh
here's this weird error that I'm seeing
at the htgp layer yes got the
correlation ID and that correlation ID
is is attached to everything yes along
that full stack that occurs absolutely
okay the thing is when you say
everything that includes the
front which means that you the front and
see front you mean the front end of the
Cent client side oh really yeah so the
client side see generated on the client
side most of the time but what this
means what it means is that it it is
controllable by the by the by
the okay let's see uh and there's no
standard so there's like a [__] ton of
of you know request different like
different type of formats geez that's a
lot of them is that is that across all
the different yeah I mean this is just
examples right so company name like they
will have you know whatever whatever
company so but yeah these are just some
of them that I that I've witnessed and
looking at them from a you know blank
perspective not knowing the company that
you're targeting you need to like figure
out what type of uh like hea it's
actually being used for the correlation
one one way to look at it is looking at
respon
they might serve you a unique
correlation ID just because you made a
request another one is like you can see
it in in the access control headers so
you can see like okay we allow these
certain headers and one of them being
the the or in this case transaction ID
but they could be Nam that's typically
in those scenarios where you're dealing
with a cross origin API oh yeah
absolutely yeah and so so these access
low headers are perfect for like
understanding what type of headers do
they actually need to work from the
frontend side or client side that's
solid yeah yeah another one is like this
is the perfect thing like as soon as you
see reflection especially when you don't
have like a validated format in this
case like whatever H this is like gold
okay H and it it doesn't necessarily
mean that you will hit gold on every
single request it means that this will
follow at some you know if you find some
obscure you're you're doing a lot of
payment things yeah yeah oh yeah this
this is the
because there will be SSH ke signing
credit cards and there it's kind of I've
definitely seen this sort of thing
before and I'm not sure if we're going
to release this on audio or whether
we're just going to do it on YouTube
since there's visual comp but um the
service transaction ID uh that he has
included here on the request side right
as a as an HTTP header is also being
reflected in the response with the exact
text so there's no uid validation
there's nothing like that and this gives
you a lot of flexibility abolutely
absolutely and this this this tells me
that this has gone you know in the back
end and behaved as this is our request
ID and we will keep this request ID and
we will also reflect it back to you um
yeah I know sh I've seen this I've seen
this many times of course yeah now what
so what I did is I start first I removed
the existing one and then I just put in
you know a lot of [__] characters but we
don't know where we're going to end up
right we don't know what context we
could be in SQL we could be in file
system we could be in you know a command
we could be in you know whatever we
don't know event Json what whatever so
we need multiple tactics we need to
figure be smart when the fussing in the
fussing so we can figure out some parts
at least uh and one one way is trigger
errors basically like you put in a lot
of you know crazy characters all over
the place uh and
then are you just doing like an asky
fuzz list like I have like all of the
asky characters encoded and then I'll
like a URL or I do I yeah basically do
this you literally just type in no no no
I do I do like single quote double quote
percentage sign like all of these things
where if that one like a percentage sign
for example if that one triggers an ER
it could be two things it could be like
sprintf or it could be a URL yeah yeah
those those are basically and for
example if an person breaks it could be
an XML context and there could be also
your um and similar things with like
dollar sign parenthesis or or curly
braces then then then you're this is
this is one of the takeways for me from
this event just from some of the life
hacking stuff in Vegas was like I need
to do more fuzzing like this and and
identification of what data is being
passed through what context because
there were a couple freaking bugs live
this this time that were just literally
straight up back to command injection
and I was like oh W no but figure out
the context it's like what it's like
so what I tend to do is like I tend to
put this in the request ID and then I go
on and do manual testing about you know
API paths I always make sure that burp
has it inside you know keeping it there
that's why you had it imagin place for
okay great so then then I can this can
happen so I can I can work for an hour
or two hours or whatever and then I go
back and like I had a 500 what what what
is the 500 why did that why are you
doing this to me man this is this is of
course this is what you got to do man of
course and then this is the fun part
because there might be add like logging
specific to some of these
end yeah I mean I get excited about this
because like I have I have not you know
made this at all like this is this is
this is we talked about before about
like I'm talking about things that I got
bored with so then I presented this is
not that yeah but the funny part is that
like you can talk about I I'm leaving
the crumbs but this is like [__] huge
go this is a [__] pie on me this is
uh so it would actually be interesting
Sor let you continue but it interesting
also to have sort of like an um I'm
thinking like an autorized sort of
approach here where you have Auto
repeating every one of the requests
differentiate them AAL between the the
status codes then you know that that was
caused by absolutely I agree really
absolutely uh and like of course there's
going to be false positives one of them
like gcp for example U not all over the
place I guess but most most of the time
on Google platform or Cloud platform
they actually validate what you send in
just just a pattern U making sure that
it's like a uu ID strong Rex matching
man it it solves a lot of problems for
sure H another one is like I've seen
this a a lot like they actually made a
border so the request ID is created on
the first you know load balancer or
whatever and then internally you can it
can be you know sent over and stuff but
on the first kind of you know entry
point no and so that is also common
those are kind of false positives well
but that's the interesting part so let's
say you have as I showed you here like
you have a bunch and then that one says
no right and then that is still
interesting because then you know that
there's another system not allowing that
thing to be happening so it's still it's
still these are still like super
interesting yeah okay we had no idea
what we were doing at first it was just
breaking and we were like where are we
we're probably in a path or
whatever uh but but then we kind of you
know let's let's let's just go through
what we found okay because these are
let's get it okay first path Traverse
Orit and this one I love this one so
yeah yeah continue go ahead go ahead so
whole idea here there was H if you sent
request ID 1 2 3 4 for blah blah blah it
would write it to trace data in the temp
file uh important part it would contain
itself so the request ID was also the
file path also inside the Json that was
written okay oh great so you got you've
got control of the path and some of the
content exactly it was the same it was
the same the reest yeah or like it was a
bunch of metrics in it but the request
ID that you sent in also work but path R
basically wrote if you did like temp
data slash and back to Temp data it
would it would write the pthe obviously
it just took the value and wrote it and
did you just force this or and um or did
you have access errors we had access to
errors okay so what we could do is like
we could go down outside of the temp
folder into the web folder put the PHP
code as the
fin 100% fine H it will then write to
trace data in TMP do the pass reverse uh
which basically meant that inside this
PHP file you would have the pth derse
but you would have the PHP code meaning
we when you went to this actually URL
with the you actually got you got to be
kidding me this is I can't believe
they're dumping everything into template
that they afterwards like a race
condition or something they they they
have like workers that dump this data
into the temp and then they have
something picking it up from the temp
folder and then sending itly so they so
the the script itself doesn't need to
connect to a loging thing they just need
to dump a file in the yeah so that's why
so uh
name too yeah yeah yeah exactly it's
like perfect H another thing we found
was a hro injection okay which is
basically you you provide they will URL
the code the header when they actually
did something with it so we had like a
client side request added to our request
ID it went into an API proxy we injected
a header there because the URL decoded
the header and then the backet service
basically so in this case we're supposed
to see account one two three just
because the request IDE was above uh it
will always take the first Heather with
that name if you get two of them so then
you can inject another account and then
you're getting their data it's stuff
that's nuts um did you try like uh
request splitting there I guess uh it's
kind of like response splitting but yeah
did you try like smuggling in another
request because I feel like you can
almost do D you can absolutely do DC uh
but no because you you just got I mean
you you got so yeah exactly but you're
100% right the the thing we could yeah
we could probably go for it seriously
getet afterwards absolutely another one
was Java so
s made like one yeah made a per awesome
Tweet back in like like four years ago
and basically he says that like if you
have Z1 z d in Java sometimes that will
actually turn into you know z z the a
um and or or 010d turns
0d uh which basically means that you can
send in c48 c48 a and it will be a new
line pared by jva dude I I I've seen
this also this came in handy really
recently with um with a JavaScript
attack that I was doing because there's
a similar weird uh Unicode sequence in
in JavaScript it's a percent or it's
Unicode Cod Point 2028 that will just
drop a new line so I love separate or
something what is it is it paragraph
separator yeah something like that yeah
yeah and I love that these work in all
these languages we need to create like a
list of these because depending on the
context there's a lot of weird there's a
lot of them yeah and he he gives some
other examples I yeah there right there
yeah yeah oh yeah drop it as well it's
awesome um another thing is playing a
simple did you where where are you
finding all
these oh my gosh
people are doing janky stuff with yeah I
know I know I love it are you
kidding
what yeah dude this is like it's amazing
oh my gosh this is like that that Ruby
thing that happened a couple years ago
with the user agent where you could just
literally put a command injection
payload in the user agent this was this
by the way so I'm not taking because I'm
like who no no no F no freaking way
insane yeah another one really
interesting yeah this one I'm interested
in I don't know where this one's going
no and and this is a subject by itself
yeah this is like a Json injection is
under appreciated undere explained and
it's freaking everywhere yeah and for
some reason I I've started to assume
that like
Java apps or platforms they have a
really hard time you know creating Json
properly without you know modeling like
if you just do a plain Json it's
actually pretty tricky in Java to do
like the easiest way to do it is to have
like an object that you have like
serialized version of being the Json
yeah it's like go where they have to
have like the the actual Json project
model structure yeah so if you just want
to make like a simple Json it's actually
like the easiest way is just string
concatenate that [__] no yeah absolutely
like that it's it's like it's a you need
to do so much things if you just want to
add a property you need to add it to the
model you need to make sure it's you
know getting but instead of like oh it's
so easy just so specifically for job
applications this I've just seen it more
I've seen it more but Json injection the
whole concept of this is that we're
actually sending in being a part of the
Json escaping the property you're in
adding our own property and then coming
back so in this thing we're actually
going down a level and then adding a new
property and going up a level again uh
and every time you do that and you don't
know the same property here you might
get like this property doesn't exist so
then you're getting an oracle of what
property you were in from the start so
so and I mean I this is I I've been
doing a lot with Jason and I'm I'm we're
coming to it I'm so excited about it so
the whole idea is basically client
client request may add the request ID
sometimes in the proxy in between or
whatever it inserts the request ID into
a stream concatenation yeah I bet that
would also be really common in the
scenario where they're they're passing
that as a Json blob from like the the
proxy on the front okay wow absolutely
and then back into the back service so
from for example one one example here is
that we the regular is having a payload
with an account and then having a side
side property called context but we then
go out of context put our own payload
and then tries to figure out that it's
account in there and then you know in
Json the last one is the one that's
going to unless you're having you know
know a property check you're making sure
there there's a bunch of libraries that
actually like oh you have double
property but but in this sense they will
just overwrite it and payload will now
be 456 instead of one
two3 uh yeah you will see there as well
JQ is just writing it over uh and yeah
so a quick how to on this is super easy
like difference between double quot back
double quote is a very good indicator
just because in Json the backlash will
always be like an escaper uh and you
also need to figure out where you are in
the context and the context could be
literally like this is just one of my
example lists of figuring out like are
you can you go two levels can you go one
level up can you go like where can you
go are properties allowed our properties
not allow so in in my fussing this is
not all of them but it it's a it's a
concept so here you can see like okay
now I'm in a a property name that is oh
oh that one should never work by the way
but whatever uh so here I'm in the
property name and I can add new
properties and I can add shine
properties uh but yeah and then and then
you're also in in so here here you're in
a list here you're in a list of lists
exct you can apply the property yeah and
then I can go up to lists and make a
string again and then then I can like so
it's all about like going down two
levels and going up or going down one
level and going up yeah and I guess
you're mostly weaponizing okay okay I
see cuz in this scenario I would think
okay we want to try to comment out the
rest of it which you no you can't some
of the you can have garbage after but
then it's super easy so then you have
you have some of them that is just
closing it you know curly braces Square
braces multiple of them because then
then you can do and remember remember
flash xss back in the day uh dude barely
that was before my face call yes yes so
do you remember how to exploit the
external interface yeah it was it was
you're breaking out of an object say A J
and this this is like bringing back some
some very fun memories of like is it a
cur brace now or a square like really
need to figure out and then it ends with
like sometimes you've been so deep and
you are allowed to have garbage so
Escape me like Curly curly curly square
square curly Square cly square and then
you're like t t I have an object and
then you're getting an error like
missing property XYZ and then you're
trying to understand in what level you
you want inject I I really the this
scenario is really it's important to
have verose erors scenarios because
otherwise you're really just but we've
seen we've been you know completely
blackboxing this and and word listed and
then then cont because
you context aware word list like
curating it based on you know
documentation their API their JavaScript
files all of these like creating these
word and also the casing of the words so
everything is camel case in you know the
regular parameters keep it as camel
casing or snake case or whatever so so
like I've been I've been creating
curated word list that could be you know
200,000 rows just with like alternative
options and spaces or is it account
underscore ID or account ID or account
typh like there's it's possible and you
can do it step by step that's the
beautiful thing because you might you
know see that one property is behaving
differently and then you know that
property is there it still won't work
but that error doesn't show up anymore
like dude this is this is one of those
this is one of those things that I can
see you get so energized
this is I toow
aser
blackbox really really really deep sort
of scenarios and I know Sam Curry also
has just sort of this sort of like six
sense and I know remember when we were
collabing together at the at the event
in Portugal just seeing you guess
freaking pths like just from intuition
it was like what is going on but it's
similar
yeah and and you need to understand like
what what what are they doing like okay
we're setting a request ID and we're
probably you know on the sides of the
it's never going to be you know in the
middle of the context request IDE is
either something that you think is
really important from start or something
that you need to have just because of
logging in the so it's like you're
always on the sides and you need to
figure out can I I cannot believe that I
didn't think to look into this earlier
because of course logging is going to
have a bunch of weird pipelines right
yeah yeah and deep and deep deep deep
deep and um and yeah here are some
examples there you can look at premature
ending what you're talking about uh and
if you know that premature ending works
then you're able to like do fussing a
lot easier yeah also but you know
because it's you know JavaScript object
notation right it it also sometimes
according to that research I want to say
it was Bion Fox I released a while back
you're able to actually use a Json or a
JavaScript comment in
some Json in Java Java has they have
like loose parsing yeah H but so yeah
you're right uh of that is also loose
there's there's that large condition and
then there's also the large condition of
um I need to to be able to not end that
comment I need to just be able to leave
it
undone I think that's probably a pretty
rare scenario but definitely worth
adding to the word absolutely n
absolutely and also duplicate properties
that could be one of the the hardest
some of them freak out about that yeah
absolutely and and you can see so uh but
one one example is like if you have D
multiple injection points you can
Shuffle the the first property depending
on where you are you can Shuffle it one
level down and then you can come back on
the level that you were because it's in
here that you want to override it so you
can go instead of going down and up you
can go up and down this if they have a
strict scheme L you're screwed anyway so
this should always work pretty much yeah
and if there have a strict schema you
need to find a property putting in there
that you can actually you know but
sometimes you're in a you're in an
property object where you are loose
where with whatever properties and then
this is a perfect thing because then you
can like Shuffle something depending on
where you are in the in the H so yeah if
you have request ID and the ID is there
and you have an yet number two you can
you can literally push ID into its own
object and then overwrite the ID
afterwards yeah that's
that's um have you have you seen
multiple injections into the same object
like that yeah 100% um so that that is
not a a rare appearence this is another
man I'm glad you mention this now
because uh I'm going to do at the talk
I'm doing for for Defcon I'm going to
mention some uses of uh match and
replace and this is a great one to like
start essentially fuzz across all the
functionality different uses of these
sort of headers absolutely wow um and
then we have est3 uploads policies maybe
of course you're going back to upload
policies funny thing was I I did I I I
talked with Matias about this like oh up
close I did you know did you do the
conditions with large and he was like
I've done I've done a talk about it I
did it on Airbnb 10 years ago and I'm
like what so and he like sent me a link
like yeah we talked exactly about the
same thing so small small here but
here's a regular upload policy you have
expiration conditions and yeah that's
basically what you have H conditions is
like an array with properties um and we
basically injected uh in one of these
they were constructing this Json as a
stram conation
so we injected our own object in there
and added our own properties the the
funny thing with3 is that you can't add
anything else than expiration and
conditions but if you add a another
conditions with capital c h it will
allow it but ignore it so you can you
can push if you can inject into an S
policy you can push everything into uh
Capital C conditions Properties or array
and they will ignore them write your own
policy semi strongly typed but it it's
it's taking this wow that's a crazy find
from it's I love that both M it was like
we both tested it and I love that and
Sweden for you JWT uh this is this is
the fun I love this one basically if
you're able to get the so now I'm not
talking about reest ID only I'm talking
about ways of like this opens up so many
other options absolutely yeah yeah or or
like you're using it and like I'm not
kidding it could be so there's so many
things with Jason injection that is
still out there waiting to be found so
this is this sounds like a you know uh
going to OAS kind of what is but this
actually works like this happens for
sure um and yeah okay that that is JW
over I feel like I feel like I haven't
seen as many well maybe I just haven't
haven't run across them but uh scenarios
where Json is being generated by a
stringing Cat Nation you you you you're
telling me that this is everywhere you
will not believe how much and think
about it you have a JWT you have like
ISS blah blah blah some people just want
to you know sign their properties
because there's another there's another
system in their microarchitecture that
wants these spe specified but you're may
be writing in Java and it's validated by
no so they're like okay I just want to
write these properties especially micos
yeah exactly so it happens more than you
think wow um and and also like systems
where XML is like more common but
they're moved over to Json they like you
can see all those sort what's the read
on the age of system that this is
occurring in like is it is it like yeah
I wouldn't say it's like the newest
systems absolutely not but that doesn't
necessarily mean that new systems are
still touched by the authorization
system is you a JWT and that yeah that's
even worse almost some of the times you
can have like I've had like if I sent
back SLU in the request ID and and it
showed up in the JWT that one has been
like the escaped again because it's like
that's parsed by something and so that
is one scenario where where you just
passed it multiple levels and and at
some point the backlash you will be
coded yeah so in those scenarios I've
seen it more yeah and actually this is
interesting one of the things that I
always do is I often end my payloads in
backslash just in case somewhere along
the thing it's not it's not uh you know
escaped specifically and will cause an
escape um so that could also be a place
you you can absolutely show and that's
that's a perfect thing like SQL
injection for example you will get an
nror just because you didn't escape the
last or you sent the escape and it was
and that doesn't always necessarily mean
it's it's vulnerable because at the end
of the day you you might not be able to
actually do anything with it you might
actually Escape you know the the single
quote might turn into you know those
scenarios are super frustrating you can
trigger an error an escaping error but
then you can't actually do anything you
can't do anything yeah yeah that's true
okay so the other one is blindly F
basically I have I I can't see the
errors it's happening you know way down
the line so I won't see if the error is
going to get triggered or not and it's
out of bound triggers we need out of
band triggers oh my go what do we have
forand Trigg you're clapping right in
front of the mic sorry Rich sorry sorry
so we have we have blind xss obviously
right we have outo band RC blind RC what
is blind RC you
say we SEC and we have L for Shell or
make L forell yeah that that's probably
last year with this like just on a
payment flow just because the old
payment system was you know nobody to
touch it exactly make your own adventure
as well um so what we found
Lo yeah that's I say like literally you
know request ID here's the here's the
and so on this one you probably just
injected a uh this dollar sign open
braces and then it aired out in some way
or did you actually just put this
payload in there I just put it put it
yeah no nothing I mean the payment went
through but it still tried to do that it
was some logging of the yeah I guess I
guess in log forell it wouldn't actually
trigger any exactly you got got try yeah
okay uh and out ofrc and that was
basically like this was okay similar to
what we showed before but it would never
trigger you know it didn't trigger an
error or whatever and and you of things
man and it just tilts
me scary it's scary that you have like
you have 25 characters that you can type
on a request and you will have a shell
on a you know large company that's
[__] that scares the [__] out that's
terrifying yeah know and you said this
is 24 later though so there's like a
like there's some sort of additional
processing it's probably a logging
logging mechanism that is or a pipeline
or whatever that just like takes all
these and has the request ID as a part
of the yeah man and blindex is going to
be huge here too because of course is
going to be the thing that is showing up
in these TR logs yeah exactly and they
might have you know built their own kind
of Trace logs Etc it's nuts course but
here's the fun part this is fun okay so
we need to optimize the blind RC because
he needs to support multiple contexts
and we still want the request we still
want you know we want to know where it
happens and why Etc so we want as few
special characters as possible we don't
want you
know very common things like for example
we we still want to support all these
different like can we inject inside the
these you know what's what do you call
them uh the backck btic yeah and then
you have single quote double quote and
also plain you know being inside the
regular bashel where inside the shell
and we need to collect data so we know
where we are like the context so same
same as plan xss we need to figure out
where why did it happen where are we
what can we do here and and here's a
perfect example of of w loock h one W
loock is literally ifs you know the F
field separator uh and you have current
braces around it that will be blocked as
hell but without current braces it won't
I don't this is always how see it with
the curly braces I didn't even know that
you could do it that way but of course
that makes sense absolutely but the
problem is you can't put uh the reason
why you want curly braces because that's
a separated saying this is the variable
so you can't you can't do the domain
after because then it will be
concatenated but I'm coming to it you
need to avoid spaces as well here's one
of my one of the one of the payLo that
works best oh the sign the sign the AD
Sign basically these becomes a separator
for the the field separator but then
just sends it to your is it just an
empty yeah empty
user my gosh and and this this is just
two example like I tend to concatenate
these two because then you can escape
signal code you can be inside double
quote the the back T will work uh if if
you're you know straight into curl this
one or St straight into into sh this
this one will work so they they
complement each other and then you you
get like a really good coverage of M
that's a good payload that's a really
nice that's really good payload so it's
so good that I wanted to have like
unique payloads every time I S
collaborator B collaborator everywhere
kind of thing so I made a pman generator
where it's like it saves payloads uh and
just so you can have a prefix and it
will just like incremental numbers save
a date for that one so you can literally
like I will payload for a wallet and it
will wallet one and two and payload
wallet and three four and so you can
just like have this and it puts it into
your um clipboard so you can just like
pay BM
insert that's solid um and then yeah
this was what it's just perfect so then
you can go back to your purp and
correlate dates and stuff or whatever
you useing kaido yeah there you go um
and then I I'm wearing the shirt
today so what you saw here also I'm
paring it to to sh yeah so I need to
have something on the side so I'm doing
a collection script uh so basically I
look if the user rent is curl and then I
provide like a very nice like who am I
where am I trying to see if like well
what's the P Etc password what's the
environment and then it just posts
you're dumping in Van that's that's
that's they trigger my code if they
trigger my code internally they it's
like we're Beyond it's scary because we
[__] made him run our that's true
at Point yeah at this point it's just
it's not it's not and also like I'm
making sure that you know if if the user
agent is basically the curl they've used
my payload to trigger this if someone is
using curl and piping my output
themselves for some other Reas like come
on it has never happened yes um and then
I connected to saier and I get like an
email like oh this is not the shell on
this IP you want to you know oh my gosh
dude and do do you think it worked I
think it worked I think do you think it
worked do you think it worked yes it my
God it was it was extremely it was so
effective they like they like don't stop
FR France please stop all testing on
this issue
[Music]
immediately anyway dude this this is
better than the Bounty right I know I
know 100% 100% so so it's like okay this
is a this is a very nice pipeline of
being able to it's almost like you know
excess Hunter kind of idea but you're
you're looking for uh a bug that
has quite High severity yeah and or
always almost and I just I literally
cannot believe that I haven't thought of
attacking this flow before because i'
I've spent especially after log forell
came out right it's like clearly yeah
everything that is being logged that
whole pipeline need it's so important
it's the reest is so important actually
I've seen some scenarios actually where
um companies really care about the
Integrity of their of their logging
pipeline as well absolutely so if you if
you have the ability to affect the
Integrity you mentioned before like the
correlation ID um being attached at the
proxy level some some don't care when
they generate on the client side
obviously that's trusted but when the
request correlation ID is generated at
the proxy level and you can find some
way to smuggle it in and override it
some companies care about that because
that screws their whole inet response i'
I've gotten messages like hey France we
saw your request coming in uh our
tracing pipeline is completely broken
you have the same payload for every
single request and you've been you know
I've been brute forcing or running like
like breath map or whatever running it
on them and and they're
like we can't open your Trace spots
because everything is there so they're
like it's useless to us can you please
have it you know run you stop can you
please change it and I'm like isn't that
a problem by itself you should get you
should M for that yeah exactly H so uh
yeah the conclusion is basically you're
basically expanding your THX surface
internally all over the place and also
like blind and error there's going to be
multiple of them H Json injection this
we need to talk about this more we need
to talk about Jason injection and um
yeah and I would love to know if there
are multiple contexts I missed some
context right sequin injection XML
injection there's going to be it's going
to be way many that I haven't thought of
I would love to hear about you know
injections happening in context that I
that I haven't talked about uh that's it
yeah dude what do you mean that is so
freaking I love that you're like I hate
that you are telling me about this right
now after live that exactly thank you
for waiting till after the live AC tell
me about this I could have been running
this on the target you weren't even in
the same
event you should look at that tet oh my
God yeah wow uh that is super awesome
think um I think we'll go ahead and
probably cut here and then we'll go do a
some some uh pod stuff related to Vegas
and stuff that but dude thank you for
sharing this freaking sick this freaking
sick thank you all
right and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscri
subber tiers which give you access to
master classes amas hack along alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there
[Music]